plotip.com 2006-12-11

# Plot IP - Privacy Policy

**Privacy Policy**   
  
**Policy Coverage**   
This privacy statement governs the collection, use, and dissemination of personal data from visitors to the Plot IP web site. All aspects of the presence are subject to these provisions with the exception of Plot IP affiliate advertisements and any other references beyond the plotip.com domain which may not necessarily indicate endorsement, in part or whole, by Plot IP of the referred sites’ practices. Questions or comments regarding privacy conduct by Plot IP beyond the considerations stipulated below should be directed via e-mail (info@plotip.com) or mail (3 Teal Lane, Essex, Connecticut 06426-1046). 

  Throughout this policy, the terms “we” and “us” refer to Plot IP, a division of PolariStar LLC. 

   **Information Collection**   
Plot IP may ask for personal information such as a visitor’s name, address, age, etc. in conjunction with a transaction on our web site either as requested by the visitor (e.g., account signup) or as requested by Plot IP (e.g., a survey). Under any circumstance the visitor --- at his or her sole discretion --- has the opportunity to choose not to provide the information for which they are prompted. By declining such a request, a visitor understands that his or her access to subscription-based services may be compromised. 

  Any submission of personal information to Plot IP is usually held for a period of a few months, but may be maintained longer pending notification of such housing at the point of data entry. Once a visitor has submitted personal information, he or she may not request that it be removed from Plot IP’s systems except when a written petition is made to demonstrate how such collection was impermissible in accordance with Connecticut State law, Federal law, or this privacy policy. 

  **Disclosure of User Data to Third Parties**   
Personal information collected by Plot IP is not rented, sold, or in any other manner distributed beyond the realms of the Plot IP staff and its parent company, PolariStar LLC, except in the following scenarios: 

  * We provide information to a third party group operating under a confidentiality agreement with us to assist in our efforts to serve content and marketing materials; such an establishment would be forbidden to further distribute information 
  * We receive a court order, subpoena, or other request from a legal body to release information or if we are in a position to defend against legal claims; we may also proactively release user information if we suspect illegal activity, fraud, or an intent to commit harm originating from one or more user(s) of our web site 
  * We transfer ownership of Plot IP and/or PolariStar LLC to another firm or forge a merger with another company; in this case, we will make prominent notification of such, including statement about how the current privacy policy may be altered 

Additionally, affiliate programs posted on our site may be targeted by geographic location, interests, or other criteria. These third-party organizations assume that users who interact with such advertisement materials fit the aforementioned specification; however, Plot IP will under no circumstance provide validation of such an assumption or any other indication --- suspected or confirmed --- about a user’s background beyond that we targeted a given ad program with the understanding that it was relevant to our visitor. 

  **Children Under 13**   
In compliance with COPPA, Plot IP will not ask children under thirteen (13) years of age to submit personal or identifying information without parental consent, nor will we proactively contact members of our visitor base under 13 with any promotional offers of our affiliates. Additionally, we strongly encourage parental supervision and/or permission whenever a child under 13 makes any form of transaction with us. 

  **Cookies**   
As part of our effort to improve service at Plot IP, we periodically post and retrieve small amounts of cookie data (a few bytes in size) on our visitors’ computers. This information is accessed solely to examine service popularity and visitor access patterns within plotip.com; these cookies are neither set nor accessed outside the plotip.com Internet identity by Plot IP or its affiliates. 

  However, please note that our affiliates (who we allow to place ads on certain parts of our web site) may set and access unrelated during a user’s visit with us. These cookies are subject to the affiliates’ respective privacy policies which are therefore not subject to the terms outlined herein. 

  **Third Party Cookies**   
In the course of serving advertisements to this site, our third-party advertiser may place or recognize a unique "cookie" on your browser. 

  **Confidentiality**   
Plot IP employs security mechanisms wherever possible to protect the confidentiality of information you submit to us. Although portions of this data may be available to our employees, it is only open in such a manner as deemed reasonably necessary for our staff to complete its assigned tasks. 

  **Policy Changes**   
This policy is subject to change when Plot IP, at its sole discretion, considers a change in its practices to merit alteration of the terms set forth herein. Whenever such changes are made, Plot IP will do its best to post notice of such in a prominent location on its website (usually in the “News” section of the presence).
